Varun Kumar R

JAVA DEVELOPER

Bangalore-560040 Karnataka

+91-8884883774

varun.ase2013@gmail.com

Experienced Java Developer with 4+ years of experience and passion to solve real-world problems by utilizing software development best practices. I have always dedicated myself to learning better ways to write clean and efficient code while keeping up with the latest tech stacks. I bring to the table my expertise in analytics, creative thinking, and problem-solving abilities. I strongly believe that learning and upskilling is an essential trait in today's world and I look forward to contributing to the ever-growing developer community. I am proactive in terms of taking initiative and I wish to make a positive contribution to the organization by working in a challenging environment where I can utilize my skills and grow along with the organization.

EXPERIENCE

August 2021-Present

DXC TECHNOLOGY — Java Developer BANGALORE, INDIA

Working on Microservices using Spring Boot framework in DXC Technology from August 2021 as **Java Developer** for DXC Security Team.

Major accomplishments and Contributions to Project:

- Writing clean, maintainable, scalable, and well-tested code by adhering to standards and best practices around development processes, coding, and peer reviews.
- Resolving technical issues, maintenance, and enhancement of automated unit tests and builds and deployment processes for applications.

Dec. 2017 - July 2021

COGNIZANT TECHNOLOGY SOLUTIONS - ASSOCIATE BANGALORE, INDIA

Worked in Cognizant Technology Solutions (CTS) from December 2017 as Java Developer for Web Portal(Underwriting Portal) of CHUBB - an Insurance Company.

Major accomplishments and Contributions to Project:

- Worked for Java Services team on Enhancement and CR required as per business requirements, in which data from DB should be consumed by Java using JPA and perform various business logic, as per business requirement.
- Worked on Java Apache POI for generation of worksheets through JAVA, as per client requirements.
- Interacting with other teams regarding CR, working on CRs and portal maintenance, SIT defects, and handling the releases sent to SIT.

EDUCATION

2013-2017 BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY – JAIN UNIVERSITY –

BANGALORE, INDIA

PASSING PERCENTAGE – 71.

2011-2013 PRE UNIVERSITY COLLEGE(12TH) – ST.JOSEPH INDIAN

COLLEGE -BANGALORE, INDIA

PASSING PERCENTAGE - 77.5.

2001-2011 | SSLC (10TH) – NEW CAMBRIDGE SCHOOL –BANGALORE ,

INDIA

PASSING PERCENTAGE - 83.52.

SKILLS and TOOLS

Beginner Level

MongoDB, Docker, LINUX, JIRA, Javascript, RESTFul API, SOAP, AWS(RDS)

Interests and Achievements

- Developed Online Education Portal as Project
- Completed NCC 'A' Certificate exam in 2011 under the authority of Ministry of Defense, Government of India
- Represented School and College at various Kabaddi Tournments, represented Bangalore South U-16 at Districts Level sports
- Published Theory paper on : Automotive-Turbocharger based Gas Turbine Engine used to produce Electricity, published for August 2016, Volume 6, Issue 8 ISSN 2250-3153

Languages Know

Kannada, Tamil, Telugu, English and Hindi.